JOSH SARNA

Pasadena, CA • joshsarna@g.ucla.edu • (262) 313-8767 github.com/joshsarna • joshsarna.github.io • linkedin.com/joshuasarna

FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER

As a web developer with a physical science background, I bring to coding an analytical mindset ideal for problem solving and efficiency. I enjoy creating algorithms and incorporating mathematical tools into things I create. In my experience, software development and math both transcend disciplinary categorization. There's nothing that can't be better understood through math, and there's nothing that can't be furthered and improved by JavaScript.

Skills: Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, VueJS, React, Angular.js, TypeScript, Node.js, Bootstrap, jsDraw, Python, Django, Visual Basic .NET, HTML/CSS, SQL, Postgres, MATLAB, Wolfram Mathematica, APIs, OOP, TDD, Git. and Heroku

EXPERIENCE

Actualize, Software Engineer & TA

2018 - Present

- TAship: Teach coding lessons to a live online class; assist students in developing their programming skills by providing supplementary instructional material, troubleshooting applications, and asking follow-up questions on coding techniques
- Middle Maps: Built an app that allows a user to search locations in Middle Earth (setting of Lord of the Rings) and to find routes between locations; learned jsDraw and Heroku and wrote an efficient shortest-route algorithm in Ruby; the backend of this app is built on Rails with a PostgreSQL database, and the front-end is built on VueJS
- **Bootcamp:** Completed the three-month intensive Actualize bootcamp and learned Ruby, Rails, Javascript, VueJS, HTML, and CSS; learned how to build front-end, back-end, and full-stack apps; gained the ability to learn new frameworks and technologies quickly

Creative Support, Supported Living Specialist

2015 - 2018

- Supported clients with intellectual and developmental disabilities in learning Java and Python
- Modernized company system by creating online spreadsheets for tracking hours to supplement outdated paper system until payroll tracking was transitioned to a fully computerized system

UCLA Program Activities Board, Community Activities Committee Chair

2016 - 2017

- Managed ten-person committee and \$1.6 million funding budget that was allocated to over 100 community service and outreach groups
- Increased funding two-fold (from \$800k/yr) during one-year tenure through a campaign that utilized projective data analysis and social media and that pushed two funding referenda through student government elections
- Streamlined application process by eliminating redundancies in application and creating extensive online instructional documentation and educational resources for applicant groups

EDUCATION

University of California at Los Angeles, Bachelor of Science in Physical Chemistry

2017

- Received mathematics minor
- Used Mathematica to model analytical mechanics problems; MATLAB to model analytical chemistry problems
- Used Spartan, CaGe, and Kintecus software applications to model chemical reactions and species